What we are going to go over and talk about are the common qualities of the multi purpose or dry chemical fire extinguishers.
Dry chemical fire extinguisher is a fire extinguisher that will handle all three classes of fire.
Class A normal everyday combustible like wood, paper and cloth.
Class B flammable liquids and combustible liquids and class C, energized electrical equipment.
This is the type of fire extinguisher that is commonly found in most places of business and everyone's home.
This extinguisher has a gage that it shows you when it is charged and ready to go.
It is a one time use fire extinguisher.
After it is used it must be recharged to be put back in to operation.
This extinguisher however, has a disadvantaged, it causes a significant amount of dry powder or chemical to be spread throughout the room of origin in the fire.
But it is the most versatile fire extinguisher available to us as American citizens.